Under the influence of the Holy Spirit, the man of God,
Prophet T.B. Joshua conducts the mass prayer in the mighty name of Jesus Christ,
exposing every demon that was hiding under the shades of darkness,
causing the oppressed to vomit up all the poisonous substances planted by the devil
and breaking every chain of bondage, setting the people free.
See the evil spirit inside this lady cry out.
Let us hear what it has to say.
I am her husband.
What did you make her do?
Prostitution.
We are three.
Who is number 2?
Dragon.
Number 3?
Manifestation of Evil Spirits
TESTIMONY CONTINUES
My name is Emmanuella Amana.
I'm from Adamawa State, the Northern part of Nigeria.
The woman standing beside me is my lovely mother, Mary.
First of all, I want to thank God for my deliverance last week Sunday.
I was two years old when I lost my father.
My mum remarried when I was 10 years old.
The man she married was a retired soldier who had children in Lagos.
The children used to travel to the North to visit their father.
They saw how their father treated me and didn't like it.
So, they told me to follow them to Lagos.
I followed them to Lagos, hoping that they would put me in school
so I could continue my studies there, not knowing that it was prostitution they wanted me to do in Lagos.
The lady I was staying with was married to a soldier.
She had a shop in the canteen, a beer parlour.
I was 13 years old then; she started giving me to men.
By then, I didn't use to drink.
She would force me to drink and told me I would get used to it with time.
I started with half a bottle and later on proceeded to drinking five or six bottles a day.
In a day, I would sleep with two or three men.
If I refused, she would send me out of her house
and I would beg the neighbours before I could sleep.
You were at the age of 13 when you were sold into prostitution.
Yes.
That was how things went until I was 14 years old
when I got pregnant by one of the men who was sleeping with me.
She sent me out of her house and told me I should go for an abortion.
I told her that I was scared, that I had never done that in my life.
She sent me out of her house.
I went to the guy I was dating before the pregnancy.
I told him what had happened and he claimed responsibility for the pregnancy
and said I should stay with him.
I started living with him until I gave birth to my first daughter.
I started going out, drinking, going out with men.
Sometimes, I would leave my baby at home with my neighbours and go to clubs with my sisters.
I would follow them to clubs.
We would drink; they would give me to men.
That was how things continued.
I took my daughter and left her father because every time, he would beat me.
I took my daughter to my mum's place in Adamawa State.
I returned to Lagos and stayed with my sisters again.
So you went and abandoned your baby with your mum in Adamawa
and returned back to Lagos to continue that same lifestyle.
Yes.
I continued sleeping with men every day - sometimes five or six a day.
I started dating a soldier - a married man.
I got pregnant fives times by him and aborted them.
The sixth one - he told me that he would see small babies in his dream, crying
and by then, I was pregnant for the sixth time.
He said I should not abort that one.
I started staying with him but he was married with four children.
His workplace posted him to Badagry and we started living together as husband and wife.
I continued drinking and I would disgrace myself.
People would question what kind of woman I was.
When I first started going to the bar, everybody loved me but with my level of drinking,
people began to hate me.
Sorry, just give us an example, sister.
How severe was this drunkenness you are talking about?
Give us an example - on a daily basis, how much were you taking?
I would drink one or two crates of beer a day.
Miss Emmanuella Amana & Mother
Deliverance Testimony
I would drink for a week without eating.
I lost appetite and never used to eat.
I would cook food but not eat it.
The soldier said the disgrace was too much and sent me out of his house with my second baby
and by then, I was pregnant.
I then went back to the North where I gave birth to my third born - a boy.
I have two girls and one boy.
I left the children with my mum.
My sister called me to come back to Lagos.
That was how I found myself back in Lagos.
That time was worse than before
because I would spend time in the hotels, sleeping with men.
We were just prostitutes because in the hotel, any girl you would see there was a prostitute.
So that's how I kept on drinking.
I became addicted to alcohol and could not do without it for a minute.
I would start drinking from the morning.
I stopped drinking beer and started on gin.
I would finish four or five big bottles a day.
That's how the thing kept on going.
Miss Emmanuella Amana & Mother
Deliverance Testimony
So we can understand what our sister is talking about.
From the age of thirteen, she was forcefully introduced to alcohol and prostitution
and that set the trend for the rest of her life,
leading to the point that at a very tender age, she had three children
and was not staying with their fathers.
At this point, sister, were you going anywhere, maybe in search of a solution
or to try and acquire powers to be able to continue this kind of prostitution job
or to get money - just explain what kind of places you went to.
I would sleep with men and get money but could not use the money for anything.
I would use it to drink.
I could not even take care of myself or send money to my mum.
I started going to churches for deliverance. That did not work.
My problem would rather intensify.
I started to follow my sister to a native doctor's house.
I wanted to make money believing that maybe it would take away the drinking and other problems.
That was why I started going to native doctors' houses with my sister.
My sister told me about a place in Kebbi State, Nigeria where they used to serve a god -
a crocodile of about 500 years old.
I found myself there because I needed money.
I went there.
I didn't even know anybody there but I started asking questions
until I found someone who could direct me to the place.
I got there and met the men there who were a hundred years old
and could not even walk on their own.
They asked me what my problem was and I told them that I needed money.
They told me to buy a fowl and some other things; they then took me to their shrine.
Before getting to their shrine, they told me to take off my shoes, shirt and bra.
The only thing that they left me with was my trousers.
I then entered the shrine.
Some people were there before me.
So, the man I followed there,
the one who was serving the crocodile said I should sit and wait.
When I entered the shrine, I saw one big crocodile with its mouth wide open.
I thought it was dead but then I saw the eyes of the crocodile move.
I saw that it was alive but I was not afraid.
I sat, folded my arms and covered my breasts.
The old man then told me to remove my hands and be free.
I agreed since I believed I would get money.
That was how I was sitting.
Within about three seconds, it was like, I was blind but then able to see -
everywhere in that forest were crocodiles.
I saw more than 100 crocodiles there.
There was a river surrounding the shrine.
Crocodiles were coming out of the river,
while some were going in, even some were passing my legs.
The man asked me if I was afraid and I told him that I wasn't.
After they finished with the lady before me, they called me.
I went to the crocodile.
I was asked my name and I told the man.
The man spoke a certain dialect with the crocodile which I didn't understand.
He would say, "This is what the master said..." - that what did I want.
I then told him that I wanted money.
He said, "Okay, no problem".
He asked me if I had the money, what I would bring him in return.
I told him that I would bring a goat.
He collected the fowl from me,
used his hand to cut the fowl's head and threw it into the river.
The fowl did not even touch the water before I saw big crocodiles, like 10 of me,
just like a cow, come up from the water, grab the fowl and go back into the water.
I thought I was dreaming and asked myself if they were crocodiles, cows or something else.
The man then went to the river, took a calabash and used it to fetch water and gave me to drink.
The remaining water, he said I should use it to bathe, which I did.
I left there.
When I saw my sister, I told her what I had done.
One, two weeks passed and I didn't see any money.
Things became worse.
I began to see crocodiles, pythons, dragons and different kinds of animals in my dreams.
That was how I started seeking for solution...
So after your encounter at this shrine where they worship crocodiles,
it was immediately after then, you began to see crocodiles in your dreams.
And what you went there for never materialised.
You never saw the money you went there for.
Yes.
I decided that since they didn't want to give me money, I would continue with what I was doing.
My sister agreed with me.
That was how we kept on going.
Things became much worse; I would drink and disgrace myself.
The people on my street would laugh at me and call me different names, like drunkard.
Even my sister who taught me how to drink started calling me names.
I started fasting and praying.
My mum didn't even know anything about what I was doing.
Whenever she asked me, I would lie to her that I was working and boast I was this and that.
So at this point, sister, how did you come to be at The SCOAN
as we saw you receive your deliverance last week?
Last week, on Friday before coming to the church on Sunday, I went to a club with my sisters.
I got drunk, came back home and decided to sleep.
When I went to sleep, I heard a voice saying, "The SCOAN".
I thought, "What business do I have with T.B. Joshua's church?"
I went back to sleep.
The voice kept on talking as if I was seeing the person.
The voice came with more power and became louder,
telling me to stand up and come to The SCOAN.
That was how I found myself here.
Let's put our hands together for Jesus Christ.
Last week during the mass prayer section, we saw on the clips earlier
how that evil spirit, the spirit of crocodile, dragon and spiritual husband
that had pushed you into such an atrocious lifestyle was exposed.
Tell us your own experience.
When the prayer was going on, what happened to you at that moment?
All that I can remember is that I was sitting at the back -
I don't know what happened; something just moved me.
I just found myself at the front.
That's all I can remember.
Ok, sister. Now to the glory of God, ever since your deliverance,
what can you say about your lifestyle and the changes you have witnessed in this short period?
After my deliverance...
I didn't even use to sleep because of the nightmares.
I would see different kind of things - scorpions, pythons.
I would even be in the midst of them - only me as a human being.
But after my deliverance, I sleep like a baby.
This urge of drinking, when I am going to church or going out to eat and I see people drinking,
I feel like stopping and preaching to them.
Miss Emmanuella Amana
Deliverance Testimony
I feel light.
Before, there was something in me.
I was heavy before but now, I feel light.
Since my deliverance, no men have called me on my phone.
Even the Saturday before coming to church, people invited me to go clubbing.
My sister called when I was in church before my deliverance, asking where I was.
I told her that I was in church.
She criticised me and said that I was missing out.
She told me some important people had come from Abuja who wished to see me.
I told her that they should not disturb me, that I was in church.
No man has called my phone since my deliverance.
Amen. Let's put our hands together for Jesus Christ!
You mean to say, sister, that for the first time in more than eleven years
that you have been addicted to alcohol, since the tender age of 13,
this week, you have not taken any alcohol.
Never.
I have not.
I don't even have the urge to take it.
Thank You, Jesus Christ.
You said that even just the week before you came,
you were still into this lifestyle of prostitution.
You mean that since your deliverance, you have stopped that life. You are no longer...
Yes.
Wow. We give all the glory to our Lord Jesus Christ.
One more time, let's put our hands together for Jesus Christ.
Truly, the evidence of Jesus Christ is lives changed.
Sister, at a young age, you have seen so much in life.
You have seen the very reality of this kind of lifestyle you were living before -
a lifestyle surrounded by drunkenness, lust, clubbing, every evil imaginable.
Now that you are here as a living testimony,
what do you want to advise our viewers all over the world,
especially those that are still living that kind of life you were once living?
My advice to the viewers all over the world, especially to those who are doing what I did,
run to God because life without Christ is not life.
It is now I know I am living a life because I can read my Bible, pray
and even preach to people now.
I don't even know how it started coming.
They should please come to God.
Clubbing, drinking, womanising and all that, is not going to solve the problem.
It will just be adding more to your problem.
It will destroy your life.
Amen. Let's put our hands together for Jesus Christ.
We have heard it all from our sister. We just want to hear a final word from her mother.
My name is Mrs Mary. I am living in Adamawa.
I came to Lagos to see what my daugther was doing here.
Since she left the house, I hadn't seen her.
She left me with small children and I suffered with them.
I'm selling leaves, firewood, everything to take care of the small children
that she left with me.
The man of God called me and asked if I could come and see the miracle of Jesus,
what God had done for my daughter at The SCOAN in Lagos, Nigeria.
That is why I travelled from Adamawa to Lagos to see what God has done for my daughter.
Thank You, Jesus! Thank You, Lord! Thank you, Man of God!
Thank you, T.B. Joshua, for my daughter.
Man of God, now she is healed!
Nothing will touch her, in Jesus' name!
Amen. Let's put our hands together for Jesus Christ!
Our mother travelled a long distance, far from the North of Nigeria,
from Adamawa State, just to witness this wonderful testimony.
And we can imagine: She had to take care of these three young children
bearing all of the burdens and we thank God today,
Jesus Christ has finally come into this matter and set her daughter free.
We thank God for this deliverance, sister.
We pray that God will give you the grace to maintain the wonderful deliverance you have received
and make the Word of God the standard for your life
and we know that as you receive from Jesus Christ,
He will continue to support you in your new life in Christ Jesus, in Jesus' name.
Shortly afterwards, Miss Emmanuella came back with her mother
to testify to the goodness of God in their lives.
Let's listen to them.
We welcome you to The SCOAN, in Jesus' name.
Please tell us your name and of the person standing next to you.
Emmanuel!
(God With Us - Matthew 1:23)
My name is Emmanuella Amana.
I'm from Adamawa State.
The person standing beside me is my lovely mum, Mary.
Since your deliverance last week Sunday,
tell us - what are the changes you have received here.
Emmanuel!
(God With Us - Matthew 1:23)
I can sleep very well. I sleep like a baby.
I don't have nightmares anymore.
I even preach to people. I am happy.
I am just like a newborn baby, now.
What about the urge to smoke, drink alcohol, sleep with men?
What do you experience?
I don't have it.
I even sit down and imagine, "Was I doing all this?"
Was I the one who used to drink and not be able to do without it?
I don't have the urge anymore.
To God be the glory. So you mean, you are completely delivered, completely free?
Yes.
That is great. Let's hear a word from your mum too.
Emmanuel!
(God With Us - Matthew 1:23)
I see the change.
My daughter has changed and she is alright now.
I am happy to see her today like this.
And we believe that what God Almighty starts, He always finishes.
As He has started this wonderful transformation in your life,
we know that the end has not yet come; better is not good enough, the best is yet to come.
What is the next step you want to take in life now -
now that you are delivered, now that you are free?
I want to start a business, to take care of myself, my mother and my kids.
We know that this problem has really grounded your life and you have no other place to turn to.
On behalf of the Emmanuel TV partners and Prophet T.B. Joshua,
it is our privilege to present to you the sum of 150,000 Naira
to start up your new life in Christ Jesus.
Emmanuel!
(God With Us - Matthew 1:23)
All that I have to say is for God to bless the man of God, Prophet T.B. Joshua,
to keep him alive, to add more years to his life, more knowledge and understanding, in Jesus' name.
I feel happy. I feel joy.
We can see that, truly, the evidence of Jesus Christ is lives changed
and our sister is weeping tears of joy.
She never believed that she could live a life of peace, security and comfort
and this is what Jesus has used this ministry to bring into her life.
We encourage you: You are delivered by the Word of God
and your deliverance shall remain permanent.
So now, continue to make our Lord and Saviour Jesus Christ the Lord of all your days,
make God's Word the standard for your life, home and family,
and raise your children up in the way in the Lord and it shall be well with you all, in Jesus' name.
Amen! Emmanuel!
Thank You, Jesus!
TT: Mel Flowers 10/04/2019
RV Robert Begier 13/04/2019